is there a reason why xss is like your
[__] or did did you like are you were
you a JS developer before or no not at
all I'm also a terrible developer in any
in any but uh what I like about this
actually we touched upon it a bit like I
like code review but also at the same
time clicking buttons and I guess that's
where that's that's where JavaScript
comes in
[Music]
right
all righty we're synced up we're s we're
ready to go all right here we are in in
Portugal we're in uh Joel's super Swanky
hotel room here so thanks for thanks for
that one man and uh we we've got uh
Renee here with us today and uh we are
all here in Portugal participating in
integrity's live hacking event um it's
been a blast so far so we'll talk a
little bit about that today um but yeah
renie welcome to the podcast man thank
you for having me renie Renee I always
say renie but it's Renee right renie is
fine too whatever whatever you like you
know whatever man we we'll roll rny pack
or whatever yeah yeah um yeah so
essentially you know we kind of wanted
to talk a little bit about uh Integrity
this episode we'll we'll cover the the
podcast um you know on this podcast the
live hacking event that we're we're
we're participating in right now and I
also want to get your experience uh you
know your take on your experience uh
with Integrity as a top Integrity hacker
there but first why don't you uh why
don't you give us a little bit of an
intro to who you are as a hacker and and
where you're you're full-time bug Bounty
right now right yeah definitely yeah so
I'm Renee Renee
Des better known as reny Pac
right 39 years old so I'm old
[Laughter]
I live in the Netherlands with my wife
and my daughter uh yeah recently well
recently one and a half years ago went
fulltime B Bounty Hunter nice uh and I
have an interesting career path going
coming from studying to be a
professional musician yeah yeah so you
told us about that you were like we were
setting up the whole you know recording
mobile recording setup and you were like
yeah actually you know I I studied like
recording and and audio audio
engineering right yeah so why don't you
tell us a little bit about that cuz
that's not exactly the most standard
path to get into into bug bny no so as
as a child I I joined the local um
Orchestra over like we have like I think
you have them as well in America like
the the the the college band type of so
I'm a percussionist so I joined as a
little kid and I I enjoyed myself and I
was good at playing percussion and then
you finish high school you have to think
like what's what's next what do I want
to do and everyone's like ah you're such
a good musician you should do something
with it and yeah you're young and you
don't know what you want to do with life
so I picked death path well it's it's
kind of interesting man I feel like the
bug Bounty industry it has an odd number
of people that are not traditional it
people that have joined the industry um
and I'm not sure if that's just because
it's accessible or whether like the
brain you know the the non-traditional
brain or something like that really
lends itself to hacking so I think it's
a bit to both yeah I think I can imagine
that yeah yeah and Joel Joel does a
bunch of music stuff too so all you guys
all you big brain music guys yeah I was
going to say I had a very similar like I
grew up I was always playing music like
I I got into music school and when it
came time to be like oh what do I want
to do um computers was basically was
like drawing me in that direction and so
I decided to go that route instead of
going the music route but I think like
that that creative type of aspect Where
You Know It music I think has been shown
to like you know increase you know
learning capabilities and all that kind
of stuff and it's really good for you
know young children as they grow up and
all that so I'm not at all surprised
that there's so many like creative and
and that type of people within the
hacking space yeah yeah well then I'm
screwed because because I no I do I do
play piano and I sing but like I uh you
know I guess my traditional music skills
are not very like essentially my the
extent of my piano abilities is like you
know I can do octaves on the left hand
and then on the right hand I just like
have the chord you know that I'm playing
and then I just kind of you know my hand
like this you know uh and hope that the
the Melody comes out but normally if you
can stay in in your key you know it'll
it's not too bad yeah yeah Co yeah so I
guess normally uh with these with these
uh interviews we like to go down the
path of like uh you know give us a
little career history tell us how you
ended up in Buck Bounty but I think I'm
gonna I think I'm gonna take a take a
little side turn today I want to hear
about some technical [__] right off the
bat um okay so you you tweeted out a
while back big bounty that you got tell
um can you talk a little bit about in in
as as much detail as you can talk about
that vulnerability what kind of own it
was tell us a little bit about that yeah
so it's actually it's actually kind of
funny so the the vulnerability that I
found is actually my profile picture on
Twitter oh really yeah so it wasn't on
Twitter but grabs phone my Prof no no I
I I actually found the same
vulnerability on multiple Pro progams uh
and technically it's like a stored xss
oh this is an nft in an nft right so
some platforms allow you to create an
nft and they do they have like systems
like lazy minting or stuff like that
where you basically only submit it to
their platform and once it's sold they
will create an actual nft for you but
what you also can do obviously because
the ethereum blockchain is accessible to
anyone so I just liked uh how do you
call it I minted my own n nfds where I
don't have to deal with the kind of all
kinds of input validations Etc sure and
just used every kind of uh cross-site
scripting payload in every kind of
metadata field that I could find and uh
a lot of these platforms like include
everything that matches a certain
standard to their platform is that the
what is that the ERC 712 721 712 721
yeah 721 721 okay yeah very cool man I I
did a little stint I guess maybe what
was it like uh it's probably 2020 or
2021 you know during the coid the coid
dark times you know into the into the um
web 3 hacking space and you know I see
there's a lot of potential there but for
me it was not like my go-to thing but
I've also seen people like you and and
uh some other names that I won't call
out directly that have really been able
to milk the web 3 web 2 Bridge that's
exactly I've had exactly kind of the
same path so I was interesting obviously
in these big bounties being paid out for
web free issues so I went to uh down the
path studying solidity and uh learning
about smart contract vulnerabilities but
I really disliked just doing code review
like I I I like I actually really like
code review when it's in a combination
with like clicking buttons or debugging
stuff and see what happens next and just
solely the code of like solidity
contracts is a was a bit challenging for
me so that's why I went down the the web
3 web two like where they meet very
interesting yeah I I've done a little
bit of web web 3 research as well and
it's such an interesting space because
there's so many different web 2
technologies that Connect into it and
you know basically in order to interface
with most of the web 3 stuff you have to
have some sort of web two interface
right like open c for example it is
purely based on like web 3 it's you know
reading information from the blockchain
it's doing all these things that are
based in web 3 but it itself is is a web
to website right and so I think that
that that sort of Gap in between is
where there's a a lot of room for those
types of vulnerabilities that you talk
about where if it aderes to this
standard right then yeah yeah and it's
also I'm really yeah it's like a
blessing on the curse I'm really into
xss and uh especially in the web 3 uh
ecos sphere is like it's yeah much more
critical actually if an if you have an
ex because there is no server s side
stuff basically absolutely and there's
so much stuff that happens with like
these browser based wall
metk and all that kind of stuff so if
you get an xss in any of those Contex
there's so much you know risk for money
loss and being able to steal funds and
all that kind of stuff so it's really
really interesting you mentioned xss so
I I wanted to call this out because you
have uh you have an xss payload tattooed
on your arm which is which is crazy yeah
yeah we'll see hopefully it shows up in
the camera if you're if you're watching
this on YouTube but yes you do have a
you have an xss payload tattooed on your
arm can you tell me a little bit about
that uh it's yeah at some point when you
have enough tatto tattoos like your
first tattoos is like you really think
about it for months and month and it has
a special meaning to you Etc I just
wanted to have a hacking tattoo
obviously hacking uh means something to
me nowadays and I wanted the xss tattoo
uh one that fits my arm so this is
basically the shortest one that I could
came up
with that's that's awesome so you know I
guess jel and I always forget this is
you know this is a podcast so we got to
appeal the audio Medium as well um so
for those of you listening and not
watching it's a it's the SVG onload um
uh payload you know one of the shortest
ones you can get um and he's using I
like the decision to go with the slash
between the G and the onload rather than
the space I think that's great I think
that that allows the flow to go fully
together well can you imagine if the
spacing was wrong too like if it's just
like a little too wide it looks it looks
very weird I was very paranoid about
when I rechecked the spelling like 10
times what did your tattoo artist think
when you came in you're like hey can I
get this tattooed to my he said yeah
whatever you like I have no clue what
what this means or what you're getting
but I'll do it yeah dude it's funny um
you know I think I've mentioned this
story on the Pod before but uh Tommy
DeVos doggy G uh he's he's the guy that
kind of got me into bug bounding the
first place because we live in the same
city and uh and he recently he was in we
were in a group chat and he um was like
saying oh yeah I'm thinking about
getting this tattoo and actually I think
he posted on Twitter as well but he at
one point he almost got the HTML source
code of a uh of a what is it the cve
details website tattooed on his arm
because he meant to get the C code for a
specific exploit but the guy went to the
website and was like oh I guess I'll
just do the HTML code so he built it in
and then he posted it and everyone's
like you're going to do HTML code on
your arm you know with like it does not
even an EXs payload he's like oh [__]
[__] [__] oh yeah and so I'm glad he did
some s check there because I also got
some comments when I posted it like
someone mentioned actually a kind of
well-known hacker mentioned that this
won't work if it's inserted in inner
HTML I was not going for a
polyglot
yeah yeah no it's funny because you said
like uh you know the first tattoo you
always like really really think about
and I've been thinking about getting a
tattoo and I want it to be hacking
related and I'm just like I'm in that
cycle right I'm like uh this would be
kind of cool and I think about it for
like you know a week or two I'm like nah
it's not going to
so you want that first one but my my
wife has a lot of tattoos and she's like
you know she just goes and gets them
like you know every couple months and
yeah she's just like oh I just I'll get
one here and one here here yeah so it's
awesome nice cool yeah man I I've been
thinking about it too and I actually
kind of even got a design you know I'd
like to do some some circuitry and then
you know integrate some HTTP request
syntax and stuff like that kind of
mapping out a web architecture but the
thing is if you if you go to Japan then
you can't get in the on sense the Spas
the the you know the hot springs the
public baths and uh dude I just love
that I love that in Japan so like right
before we went on this trip to Japan
which we just got we just you know flew
from Japan straight to Portugal uh I was
like yeah you know I should I'm really
close to doing I think I'll do it within
the next like couple months and then I
go to Japan and I'm like sitting in the
hot tub thinking like it's not worth it
it's not worth it to me
man so I don't know man I guess it's a I
guess I if Japan ever changes their
policies then I I think I'll I'll go
down that route um all right let's let's
uh let's bring it bringing it back
around um so you are um you know top 10
uh I guess in in Integrity not not more
not anymore actually not anymore I'm
11th he's 11 top of course done with the
top 11 in Integrity um you've been
working on the platform uh you know for
quite a while um and but you've also
done I think I saw in a tweet you've
done some hacker one stuff you've done
some hacken proof stuff um talk to me
about I guess the experience of working
there's like a fly here uh there's about
the experience of of working on
integrity and versus The Experience
you've had on other platforms and kind
of lay out the differences for
me U I'm actually a big fan of Integrity
because on other platforms I often had
the feeling that they would treat me
like uh well just like clearing the back
law y well at Integrity there's really
the triage team and the support te also
always really personal especi yeah I
think it would also help that I'm in the
top because they know me and they help
me and that that obviously helps but in
general they're really really open to
feedback they help you along and they
have some custom message for you oh nice
to see you back on the program or
whatever not like just the the thank you
for your message number yeah so that's
that's something I really like and I
think I think I started at the right
time uh at Integrity to to be able to
grow along with the program with the
platform to to reach like uh the top 10
yeah and and that helps yeah so how did
you find out about integrity like what
led you to even hack on integrity versus
hacker one or bug Crow or any of the
other ones so there actually a kind of
funny story as well I was uh working at
ball.com which is like a well the tiny
version of Amazon within the Netherlands
and Belgium cool um and I was working on
the security team there also managing
the BG Bounty program got it and there
was this dude also at the event captin
uh who submitted some reports uh and uh
they were all valid and accepted and
whatever and at some point he needed an
internship and asked through hean to uh
to get an intership at our team which uh
he got okay and he actually was already
active on integrity and suggested I
should have a look as well okay
interesting so you were running a bug
ring program on hacker one yes and then
he was like hey you should check out
this platform Integrity wow wow that's
very interesting wow okay very cool so
then you started hacking on integrity
and were there did you stick to one
program or like no I I often tried to
like the top hackers that are really
focused on one program I I can't manage
to do it I have like like to my
attention span is too short we all
have I was I was talking with with uh
with Rene in the car you know I was
saying like so many of the top hackers
have like this they're just absolutely
brilliant and you know we've had this
conversation before Joel I I even feel
this way with you like like I feel like
my thing is not necessarily like the you
know engine burning really hot you know
or the oven burning really hot but the
ability to like stay focused or stay
committed to something and it's amazing
when when you know you guys can actually
direct that that power at at stuff I'm
always like in awe so yeah but it does
come with the side of like you do have
to jump around from pram to program some
time to time so yeah for well for Life
hacking events I I do one to force
myself to to focus on the target so yeah
and I I do it from time to time but yeah
I'm not I'm not the type of guy that to
can totally get into one program so do
you do lots of events lots of like
hacking events uh I've done like five or
six Integrity events okay um yeah Hecker
one event all of them I think right yeah
no yeah they have had a bunch but it was
I started during Co I guess some virtual
ones yeah yeah yeah yeah so yeah Hecker
one event is high on my bucket list but
I guess I'm not active enough on hacker
one yet to uh we like the status match
that Airline programs
have that's that's true I I've been
thinking about that so we we'll see you
know how that goes but I mean obviously
if you can hack one place and you can
hack in another place but I will say
there is something about live hacking
events like you can see hackers that are
phenomenal at at um well even it goes
both ways you can see people that are
phenomenal at hacking in a normal
context but then when you put them in a
live hacking context they they can't
they can't do it or the opposite as well
is true you see some people that are
like so motivated by the competition
right and they're like oh this is like
amazing like I can totally stay locked
in but then you know off off platform
you know or off off the live hacking
events just on platform it's very hard
for them to stay focused so it is it is
a little bit uh of a trade-off as well
there and I'm curious so going back to
the question about um you know you're
jumping around from program to program
like we've had people on the on the
podcast that are pretty extreme with
this for example Douglas day AR
Archangel uh he says he'll give it like
you know 30 minutes to 3 hours or
something like that right before he
switches programs if he doesn't find a
bug and then we've also had people I
think maybe the most uh clear example of
this would be Alex Chapman or even me
who are like yeah I'm going to sit down
for a couple weeks and try this program
until you know I either beat it or it
beats me so where do you fall in that
Spectrum um depends on the mindset of
the day a bit Yeah but typically I'm in
the in the days area okay but I'm also
yeah some days you have like especially
being a full-timer at the end of the day
you think I think what have I done I've
just skipped over like a hundred
programs checked out the scope asked for
cren credentials and then moved on yeah
of the day yeah that's really
interesting I've actually been having a
lot of conversations with hackers at at
this event who participate in both
integrity and hacker one events and all
that kind of stuff and uh the i' I've
felt that over time the more events that
I do it's actually very difficult to
like get to get to that deep dive State
because oftentimes you'll be doing an
event and then there's another one
coming up and you just have to start
prepping for that and you have to like
you know either focus on that one
singular Target which is kind of a deep
dive but it's not really the same when
it when it's forced in a sense right
where like you know essentially you're
being told oh you you need to hack on
this where it's like you know I might
have ideas about a program that I'm
really interested in but I can't hack on
it because I don't have you know the
time or you know I need to be focusing
on this other program so um do you take
notes how do you how do you deal with
that when you're going in between events
and full-time hacking I take notes I try
to take notes but yeah it's like I've
heard other the hackers say the same
thing it's like the notes. text yeah
with some random stuff in there and uh
yeah I did when I became fulltime I I I
did make it a habit to just put it in a
Google Drive auto sync configuration so
I can look back at it typically I don't
really use it a lot but yeah it's it's
it's crazy that that's that we've
actually seen that across so many top
performing hackers I really would have
expected that and I guess joelie you're
pretty much the closest thing to this
with how organized you are with your you
know spreadsheets and stuff but um we
haven't seen many many hackers that do
very structured notes very detailed um I
think one hacker comes to mind with this
and it's mayonnaise on hacker one I know
that he takes extremely structured notes
and even does um data science on all of
his like burp uh you know files and like
you know all that sort of stuff so
that's pretty crazy we might we might
should get him on the Pod for like a a
counter a counter take on that um but as
as a full as a full-time Hunter you know
you mentioned you're a full-time Hunter
um I guess as a full-time Hunter myself
I know that there's a lot of struggles
that go along with that and we've seen
just looking at the history of that um
how few
you know people actually make it the
whole you know even a year in in
full-time bug bounty hunting um so well
what and you you say you've been doing
it for a year and a half so tell tell me
about your experience and tell me about
some of the struggles you've had with
that for me the most challenging part is
working alone while on the other hand
it's also like a con so that's the thing
I'm I actually struggle with the most so
last winter in the Netherlands I was
still working from home uh and I'm in
the
and it's raining outside and it's dark
and yeah there were many times where I
thought to myself what am what am I
doing with my life what yeah so I tried
to change that actually so since last
May I'm now in a in a flex working
co-working space office which is
actually kind of nice especially so I
can have a commute to work and clear my
mind when going home Etc so that's nice
still working alone still everyone is in
their own doing their own thing but it's
a it's a nice change of pace during the
day so is that kind of like a wew work
type thing that I don't know if you know
that we have this in the US no yeah mine
is called spaces I don't know it's also
kind of international but maybe in
Europe but yeah it's something like that
yeah I have my own dedicated cubicle
basically on the floor with all cubicles
okay so just like a little oneman office
type okay very very very cool is it like
a monthly fee or how does that okay
that's really cool i' I don't actually
think I've heard of many hackers who do
that and I kind of like I know a lot of
people like the structure is like huge
for for being that like I'm not like
that at all when Co hit I was like oh I
have to stay inside okay sweet like say
less you know like that that's totally
like how I am but I know a lot of people
were just like dying to like just like
get outside or like get back into like
the social interactions that kind of
stuff I actually wanted to ask about
that like I've struggled with that
decision myself to go do a we you know
Wei work or like a you know
collaborative workspace um and I think I
I don't have kids so I'm sure this might
change when I have kids but um like do
you mind if I ask how much that costs
every
month is like uh in dollars no no no no
like 400 EUR or something 400 EUR okay
so that's that's yeah like I would I
would definitely struggle with that
decision even though 400 EUR is not you
know too much pay for that sort of thing
as well I did as well actually and uh
because I had to pay like you commit to
like a year or something oh really wow
but uh it was actually around the time
when I make the 50k so I just said to
myself well let's do this times 12 see
what the total amount is and then I'll
just I took that from the from the
Bounty put it in a separate accountings
or savings account and then I was like
done I keep it get rid out of it out of
my hat and uh this is it that's fun yeah
I was watching a video today that was uh
was very it was like a plumber or
something in New York City but but he
was basically saying like just to like
walk out the door and get in his car and
like go go do a job is a minimum like
$1,000 a day just in you know parking
and insurance and Fe and all that kind
of stuff and so like if you sort of
extrapolate it out like I think that's
almost a good way to think about it
where it's like okay if it's say 400
euros a month or whatever it's 100 euros
a week that's like you know your
operating cost basically it's like okay
I need to make 100 euros this week and
that's it if I don't make 100 euros this
week I make 200 Euros next week right
and so like you if you can frame it that
way I think that that kind of helps
because setting those those goals is
really good one way I like to think
about it is you know I sort of frame it
as like a yearly salary like say I want
you know X dollars per year divide that
by 12 or divide it by 52 weeks or
whatever okay I need to make this much
per week I need to make this much per
month and that's sort of like you know
if I get a bounty that's that much or
more I'm like sweet I'm you know I don't
have like if I make more that's great
but if I don't like I know that I'm
going to hit you know this much per year
and that's like it's a lot easier for me
to have that sort of system in my mind
where um it's more like split out and
it's almost like a salary type thing
instead of grind I think a lot of people
when they think about doing full-time
bug bonding they're like oh well where's
where's that next Bounty coming from
where's that next like paycheck like
there's no paycheck right and so yeah I
think if you if you have it like that
where it's like you know you have
monthly things that you know you have to
pay for and all that kind of stuff it's
nice to kind of structure it yeah I do
it exactly like this so before I started
I I made sure I had the financial buffer
to be able to fail basically so at the
time the buffer was like 6 months or
something and now the buffer is like a
year or something but I also just I give
myself myself a salary a fixed salary
and then I'll just keep filling the
buffer uh and doesn't matter if it
overflows or if it gets a bit less but
as long as it's a solid amount of money
in there then uh I'm content I guess
that's that's really interesting I I
actually have a different approach to
this um I guess I do still have all the
money come into my company and then I
pay myself a normal amount out of that
account but I also found it a little um
stressful for me if I say okay I want to
earn x th000 a year and then divide that
by 12 and then you know this is what I
need to make every month because of the
volatility of PK Bounty right and so
like for example if I you know if I've
got six bugs 10 bugs 15 bugs in the in
the pipeline but and it switches over to
October or whatever and I'm like H you
know I didn't make as much as I needed
in September then it kind of stresses me
out a little bit so I I try to look look
at it more from like a a holistic
perspective of like I have enough money
in my buffer you know to make it through
you know the end of this year for sure
and then I look back on the year and I
say okay I made x amount that past year
um you know I'll try to shoot for
because it is helpful to have goals you
know I'll try to shoot for roughly you
know X Plus One X plus two you know 1.5
time X or 1.2 time x you know for the
for the next year um but breaking it
down into individual months for me is
just like oh cuz yeah because it just it
it it really you know if I don't hit a
goal I'm like come on yeah yeah I I I
don't look at it from a monthly
perspective like I I look back a year
typically to see how I'm doing but yeah
I'll I'll keep the monthly payments the
same so I don't have to worry about
what's coming in yeah so I mean on the
topic of money you I think you posted on
Twitter that you're you know looking for
a job or doing consulting or stuff so
was that monetarily driven did you just
want to kind of reduce that stress or
what what it's actually related to what
we're talking about
so the the thing I struggle with is like
working alone like all your colleagues
are also your
competitors and are like on the other
side of the world so I can uh I can't
easily ask them a question and so that's
the like the main reason where I was
looking into getting a job again uh but
I also posted it like just see what pops
up right I'm not at a stage where I'm
desperate to have a job or to desperate
to change something overnight because I
can't uh take it anymore just like I
said it it's it's a bit I'm a bit
conflicted with the working alone
because it's also I also really like it
I also really like not having to deal
with meetings that I don't care about
not having to report to a manager that
has an opinion on my performance so
that's that's the plus side of bug
Bounty obviously dude I the meeting
thing it's it's so foreign to me man
like I I was talking to a friend in
Japan the other day who's like yeah
there's this guy in my organization that
like will ping me this isn't isn't even
his Superior this is his um you know
same level dude and he'll be like hey um
we're going to have a meeting in 10
minutes and it's going to be an hour
long meeting and and and he just drops
it on him like that and I'm like dude
you gotta you got to say no to that like
you got to like there's no way I could
live my life you know with like but on
the other hand also you know if I've got
a meeting on my calendar it's like oh
okay I've got a 4-Hour block here what
can I accomplish in a 4H hour block you
know and and the 4H hour and and the
reason why you know that affects me is
because it does take so much Focus to do
B bounding like I find it very hard to
jump in and out of a flow State you know
of your focus state in bug Bounty so I
definitely I definitely understand that
there yep yeah so speaking of Flow State
what is like what's your wow I just went
went through puberty
again wow U so what
sorry so what what is your uh what does
your hacking like flow actually look
like what you know when you approach a
Target what's what what is your mindset
how do you look at the Target what are
the first things you do um what are
things you look
for I think I'm always really interested
if people have a good answer to this
because I I I don't really have a good
answer so broad right the question what
I TP I I like yeah we talked about xss
I've I've built some browser plug-in
tooling to help me find stuff I also
posted it about about it on Twitter a
few times so typically my flow is just
clicking buttons in a
website and basically having burp open
uh checking the output of some of these
plugins that I've built and that's
basically how I get into the application
a lot of top hackers have that answer
and and that the question that we ask we
we pose you know to see if anybody has a
quick answer to get have structure
because if they do that's really cool
but so many of the top hackers say
exactly what you said and that's great
for the top hackers right but I'm also
as I've worked with mentees and people
that are trying to get that sense I
wonder how you came to that so so do you
do you let's think back you know uh you
know you you've been studying music
forever and now you're you know you're
going into into bug Bounty related stuff
you know I guess maybe you had a job at
at Bull insecurity beforehand but um how
did you when you first approached a
Target was it was it similar or did you
use a checklist or how did how did you
how did you know what to look
for it's a hard question I'm sorry I I I
Know It's Tricky yeah I guess it's
something you learn over time yeah uh
what really helped me and still helps me
is sometimes I like I said I I've built
some browser extensions that do stuff
basically and to to read uh refine the
output a bit to look into uh alerts
popping up I think that really helps me
to yeah get a sense of what's happening
it's an interesting question actually I
I I guess I have that sense for xss and
there are so other hack is also at the
event I once had a discussion about uh
with Kur matai he was also at the event
he really really good in SQL injection
yeah and I was like dude SQL injection
does that even exist still exactly same
yeah and he's like testing like a single
uh quote somewhere and gets one bite
difference in the response is like yes
that's an es injection no way dude what
a beast yeah I I got to I got to meet
them there's so many people here that I
don't actually have often because we
we'll mention this as well the event is
uh is a sort of it's possible to selfs
sponsor yourself to come to this event
you know you're it's possible to pay the
you know amount for the ticket in the
hotel and come over here so there's so
many faces here that I haven't actually
seen at the live hacking events before
but I see on Twitter all the time um so
I've really there's been so many people
I I want to meet but it's interesting
that xss stood out to you specifically
from the beginning and that you actually
went through the the process of creating
tooling specifically for it is there a
reason why xss is like your [__] or did
did you like are you were you a JS
developer before or no not at all I'm
also a terrible developer in any in any
but uh what I like about this actually
we touched upon it a bit like I like
code review but also at the same time
clicking buttons and I guess that's
where that's that's where JavaScript
comes in right so I have some solid
issues on like open source stuff where I
could also do the same basically but
then on the surface side so that that's
nice but yeah typically yeah that's what
I like about xss also because JavaScript
is so it's it's so crazy you can do like
anything you can have like a million
ways to the same goal yeah I like about
I like that about it that's really so
can you tell me a little bit I don't I
don't don't know if you're comfortable
with sharing so many of your secrets or
whatever but what are some of these
extensions or browser plugins or
whatever that you that you've written to
help yourself so one I've one that is
actually really basic but it just uh
monitors every URL the browser fetches
okay and if it has any query parameters
and then it will inject just like a a
harmless payload into every query
parameter and see if it's reflected so
like the reflector plugin from burp but
what I like about keeping it in the
browser is that in burp you constantly
have to switch Focus you have to see if
is this valid something and and now I've
just built it like it will literally pop
an alert saying xss here while I'm
clicking button so sometimes and when I
approach a new Target and I'm clicking
button I found my first few xss is just
by browsing uh the application got it
and so does it basically just like put
the quy parameter in your payload so
that you know which where it's coming
from or how do you yeah so it alerts
like the the URL with my injection yeah
so that's really nice yeah and so and
another one I did is like an extension
on France rosen's uh post message
tracker dude I love that yeah so I
recently I I really like the extension
what I dislike about it is that you for
every page you visit you have to click
it open to see if something pops out to
you so I made like a really small
adaptation that will just look for a lwh
hanging fruit like xss syns like eval or
whatever and if it's in there already
then it will pop up an alert and just uh
yeah prompt me to check it out and yeahp
I've been a bit obsessed with post
messages the last few is so fascinating
I I have been too and it's like I feel
like there's a lot of unta potential
there especially
as these move toward a framework you
know every every that you you you work
with now is using like you know react or
angular view whatever these single page
apps you know it's kind of hard to get
anything besides Dom xss so being able
to do Post message stuff is really that
that really helps a lot and expands the
xss scope quite a bit Yeah there's so
much still so much lwh hanging fruit I
was really surprised about it and also
seems like every like a lot of websites
have this support chat button thing it
seems like all these providers are
vulnerable somehow well yeah because I
think it's really interesting that we've
seen browsers increase security like
cross window cross tab all that kind of
stuff but in order in order to do that
and keep things functional and make it
so that you can have like a nice user
experience where you know PayPal
checkout for example you click the
button it pops up a window well it has
to communicate somehow right and same
thing with these chat support buttons or
the wallets or met all the stuff that
we've been talking about these things
have to be able to communicate somehow
and often this ends up being post
message and so it's it's like a very
widely used piece of technology but I
think it's quite underexplored um and
insecure by default oh yeah absolutely
right like there's no default checks
it's not checking for origin all that
stuff is up to the developer and so so
many de developers are just like it's
not even on their radar right it's not
even something that they know they
should be looking for or even concerned
about because I don't I don't think it's
very intuitive that you would expect oh
you know some random website might I
frame my website and then start talking
with it right like it's not really an
attack scenar that you're you're going
to think about and so I think uh it it's
super super underexplored and there's a
lot of research to happen there yeah
thanks for thanks for looking right at
me when you say there's a lot of a lot
of research to happen there Joel Joel uh
knows about uh and I'll I'll share this
with you offir uh Renee but there's
there's a piece of post message related
research that I've been working on and
that I've finally got to a place where
it's like oh this is g to break some
[__] um so uh that'll be coming soon uh
I'm not ready to to to talk about that
one uh super super much yet but the the
post message space is is truly
fascinating and there's a lot of vones
there and like you highlighted Joel if
you understand the concepts be behind um
you know browser security you know your
your same origin policy and you see hey
this these Pages somehow are
communicating between the two of them um
that should ask you you should ask why
why is that happening how is that
happening no um and often times the
answer is is post message so definitely
a cool a text space there do you have
before we move on I guess do you have
any so obviously you made a modification
to the post message tracker by fron
Rosen um and that's that's a great piece
of of software for people to install um
to even just get introspection into how
post messages are are working on the
page do you have any other uh tips or
tricks you've run across in the post
message Arena that you'd like to pass
off or or is it mostly just
understanding the logic of each individ
page I think that's the that's the thing
uh also yeah like you said the origin
check is like the key factor almost in
uh in this stuff and that's what we're
talking about like getting a sense for
stuff like now the past weeks I've been
hyper focused on post message and now if
I get the the popup I instant see like T
do origin or Okay this not this one yeah
yeah yeah that's awesome I mean there's
so many things that just I think come
intuitively to us that now that we've
been doing hacking for so long that you
just you see post message you're like oh
okay like I I know how this works or I
know how this is probably going to work
um and it's it's fun we were we were
hacking with FRS yesterday during the
event and well during the pre-event I
guess and uh he guessed a he guessed we
were doing like a path uh what secondary
context path reversal and path
substitution and he gu he he realized
okay it's three paths up and he guessed
what the legitimate like API path that
was being used in the back end was just
based on like oh yeah I think this is
probably how this works and he just was
like trying different stuff and we
couldn't actually brute force it because
there was a rate and so he was just like
manually testing some stuff and 5
minutes later he was like oh I got it
like wait what it's like this totally
internal end point it's crazy crazy yeah
dude that blew my mind and and it and it
really shows like you know people have
different intuitions at different spots
and it's all about you know when you're
growing as a hacker it's all about sort
of fostering those intuitions um and I
will but go going back to what we were
talking about with the post messages
origin thing I will say I I normally I
do the same thing right where I see like
you know whatever t. origin whatever all
right whatever like I'm I'm done with
that just throw it away but lately I've
been I've kind of looked at a little bit
closer at some of this stuff and I've
seen so many developers get regular
Expressions wrong in that context um if
if you see An Origin being compared to a
a regular expression um and they're not
escaping the dots there's going to be
problems there and I just it's that same
you know age-old story of like thank God
for whoever came up with dots to be to
be any character in regular expressions
like it's the most legendary thing ever
and I'm so grateful for it um so
definitely be on the lookout for that
one when you're checking out post
message stuff um okay so I wanted to
actually ask you about two tweets that I
had you know when I when I stalk you on
Twitter before we you know we do the
interview um you had so one you've done
recently was a sort of an xss scenario
where you're like where you had the
following conditions recently
encountered I'm just going to read the
Tweet recently encountered a challenging
stored xss case no dots no parentheses
no plus no single quote no space and
wait was that no space character or no
space character okay I
say cuz the next line says Max 35
characters which is no space um and then
unlimited amount of payloads that can be
stored every payload is reflected twice
yeah which is so funny because as you
were reading through those I'm going
through my mental checklist I'm like oh
I know a bypass for that I know a bypass
for that oh that cancels my oh oh oh I'm
running out of
bypasses very intense you know xss
scenario um and you know you represented
most of it here in the Tweet but uh talk
to me a little bit about your your
testing procedure for that and can you
tell me like how long it took you to
actually get to the solution you put in
the Tweet quite a while actually so we
we're having a we have a Discord server
with quite some hackers and once a year
we we tend to meet up in a big Villa in
the Netherlands and people fly in from
all of it like some last year people
from America flew in it's really nice
and this year we got yes we hack to
arrange us some fresh targets to hack
awesome so this was a really nice
program uh and I was basically well in
my same flow again just pasting stuff in
there and uh clicking buttons uh Harmony
is also in this event he was he reached
out to me saying uh dude you're escaping
HTML here so maybe you have an s and
then we looked into it it was like it
was like a me field meant for an
identifier so it would do stuff like uh
uh replace space it with underscores and
stuff like that so and it like if you
added a the plus symbol it would just
write out Plus in letters and stuff like
that so it was really challenging setup
uh but we could like use enough
characters to or we could put in enough
pay loads to like yeah get a full
payload in the end uh so yeah we had
quite some challenging stuff to work
around all these uh things that's
awesome I love that that little uh you
know Hacker House type thing we've done
that a couple times uh throughout the
years at different events often times
we'll do it after the event we did that
in Japan we went to hakan and um that's
where we recorded with lopin and um you
know just it's it's awesome to have that
kind of it's a lot more relaxing than
the actual like def Right In the Heat of
the events and to just be able to kind
of hang out and still have those kind of
hacker discussions and stuff you have um
what is it a hacker Hideout I think it's
called is that is that what that is no
okay I would wish I would wish it was
that now it's actually kind of hacker
Hideout also originates from uh my
quests to get an office space actually
because I was looking for an office
space and I was thinking like how
awesome would it be if you have like an
office for buck Bounty hunts like a flex
working space where people could just
drop in hire an office for a day or
something and then and then I was
looking into that because yeah I needed
my own office space so maybe I can
create like something to do that uh with
others and then I found out that like
the full-time book Bounty community in
the Netherlands is like five people or
something oh yeah all over the world you
know it's it's it's kind of Hit or Miss
so I I I'd be really but but I think
actually there are a decent amount of
people that are in offensive security
you know and so and and those those
positions do tend to be remote you know
and so you maybe there's some
possibilities there the idea got
converted I I started did together with
the host also at the event here to First
just try to build a small community uh
we didn't want to open up a Discord and
allow everyone in but just like a an in
crowd of people uh and maybe well maybe
do like just do like fun stuff like the
Villa party we also do like meetups or
whatever so in this event we we well we
started out with creating our own uh our
own hacking team basically so yeah yeah
that's great man yeah I I I hope that
that takes off because anytime you can
get a bunch of hackers in a space
together it really does you know crazy
stuff happens sh all the time I mean
that's like why we started the podcast
too was we wanted to be able to sort of
extend these conversations that are able
to be had by hackers behind closed doors
with the rest of the community so that
they can learn from it because there's
so much value like every time I come to
one of these events and I'm talking with
people even if it's just like 20 30
minutes it's there's so much like
hackers have a level of understanding of
what each other are doing to so much of
a degree that you can just immediately
like even if like we've never met this
is the first time we met we can just
have this conversation and we know
exactly like what where the other one's
coming from because we've like been
through that same kind of hacking
experience and it's so awesome to to be
able to have those same connections with
so many hackers and it's so like the the
the knowledge sharing is just incredible
like I I don't even know how to Express
like how valuable the knowledge sharing
is between hackers at these events and
so you know I think it's really
important to create a space that Fosters
that kind of you know that energy and
that kind of you know Community where
you can have an open space where you can
talk with hackers and you can
collaborate you can share ideas and
bounce stuff off of each other yeah yeah
it works great and also also within our
team now I think I'm I could say without
being like uh proud without flexing I'm
I'm the most experienced Buck bounty
hunter in my team but uh the most
brilliant ideas came from teammates is
isn't that crazy isn't it crazy how that
always works like it seems like when
when you work with some of the the newer
people like as you're re-explaining
stuff you're like oh wait why do I think
that way you know and so and not even
when you're explaining but just when a
fresh set of eyes is on the scenario
that's really helpful definitely I
really like that also also with the xss
payload that we just discussed the the
very limited one I I deliberately post
those on Twitter just to get a feedback
and like Yan Carlson is also at the
event like in the First with I but you
could just URL Escape or URL encode the
dot and then you're done
like thank you this would saved me like
five hours of my life love that for me
thank you thank you no that's that
that's great man it is great when we
have the community together yeah well
and it's it's really funny because me
and you me me and Justin we hack we hack
a lot um together and we do a lot of
pair hacking often times it's not even
that we're like both at our laptops but
I'll just be like sitting next to him
we'll just be sort of observing and I'll
be like hey you know maybe you could try
this or you could try that and he'll do
the same thing and I think it's it's so
valuable because when you have been
working on a bug for like hours or days
or whatever you you make a lot of
assumptions right where you're like oh I
you know this is probably not happening
or you know I'm like 99% sure that this
is a case or you just you know you don't
even think about it because you're very
focused on like a go a goal yeah and
then when somebody new comes in they'll
start asking they're not dumb questions
but they're you know they're sort of
like you know they don't have the same
kind of background context that you do
because they haven't been looking at
that bug for so long and often times
those are the most valuable questions
where they'll be like well have you just
tried this and you're like oh why why
haven't I tried that I probably should
try that what the case here as well
you're like committed to the the the
path you're taking like you have to the
payload is halfway there so you're not
committed or not prepared to give up on
it or like so you make it work somehow
yeah the the only so we're coming to a
wrap here and uh the only other thing
that I really wanted to make sure we hit
on this podcast was sort of talking
about the Integrity event that we're
we're at right now we talked a little
bit about integrity as a platform but um
I guess just some thoughts from for the
community from this event what for me is
that uh one of the coolest things is
that you know people can pay their way
their own way like we talked about and I
think there's there's some pluses to
that and there's some downsides to that
right the plus is that you get to see a
lot of new faces you get to see you know
the people that are successful in the
industry and that contribute on Twitter
and stuff like that but haven't
necessarily been at the life hacking
event scene yep um that's really great
the downside of that though is that
there are so many hackers and especially
if you have a scope that's a little bit
more constrained which would normally be
great for a normaliz live hacking event
I think when you open it up to so many
people the dupes start getting a little
overwhelming so that's one thought for
me it's challenging yeah I think I heard
yesterday that there was a bug that got
uh it was like $1,100 and everybody got
$11 which I got split a 100 times which
is I think the lowest Bounty I've seen
is like four
63 yeah and and I think some of those
ones you know they're they're fixing
some stuff uh I I had a conversation
with them this morning but um one of the
other things they did at this event was
that they had a channel in slack for uh
knowledge sharing and that knowledge
sharing was incentivized by by bonuses
yes and man did that save our butts this
event um so really like to see that um
and I've got a couple other things as
well but did you did you have any
thoughts you wanted to share about this
event yeah I I thought uh indeed the
sponsored non-sponsored thing was really
interesting for me personally I wouldn't
have attended if it was self-sponsored I
guess because yeah my reasoning was this
is a job for me and to pay to be able to
perform a job was a yeah a bridge too
far for me basically so so I wasn't in
the first batch of invites and then the
cell sign up uh period started and I was
like well let's just pray I get an
invite in the second B and then I got
invited luckily so that's nice that's
awesome yeah I'm actually really
surprised you weren't in the first batch
of invites cuz I mean you're so high on
the inte Integrity platform that I mean
it's very Hit or Miss I I was at one of
the very first ones I don't even know if
I can say the target it was the banking
app is what I'll say um all right yeah
and uh that was that was really
interesting but um I you know it was
kind of the first time they had ever
done anything like that it was very you
know small and and and this is such a
different type of vibe to that where
it's you know it's very big it's very
you know there's so many people and I
actually I do like the self sponsor
thing I'm actually self sponsored for
this one um you know part of it is half
vacation half you know getting to see
hacker friends you I've never been to
Portugal so it's fun and I had a bunch
of miles that we're just sitting around
doing nothing so yeah I think if you can
make it work you can make it work but
it's nice to offer that opportunity for
you know if people really really want to
be here absolutely you can pay to win if
well yeah pay to arrive you know maybe
not win but but yeah you can definitely
pay to get here and uh you can sort of
you know show that you have the
capabilities I think it can be really
really difficult for new hackers to
break into the live hacking space
because there's so much competition here
and the people who are hacking at these
events all the time are just insanely
talented um and so you know getting a
spot can be very very difficult unless
you're doing full-time hacking or unless
you find a bunch of crazy bugs in a
short period of time right so yeah
absolutely man there that's definitely
been a big piece so cool to see it go
sort of both ways there you know getting
to see everyone's you know face and that
sort of thing but also seeing the the
downside of like oh well I guess maybe
sometimes 40 40 people live hacking
events is not is not so bad no
definitely yeah so so one other thing
that I saw as well and we'll we'll come
back to you as well see if you got
anything else to share but one of the
thing that I saw was that they have uh
or at least they're supposed to later
today have a little sort of help desk of
sorts for going and sort of debating
your bugs oh really so so normally you
know you you've got to go and you got to
be like for any of you that for anyone
that's been to a live hacking event you
know how this works but you know it's
like knock knock knock bang on the door
like hey I need to talk to someone about
that you know like and then you get to
have a conversation right and then you
know you resolve it but I I thought it
was really really cool that um you know
they sent out a message saying hey there
should be a dedicated time later today
to discuss some some changes to your you
know severity or maybe is it a dupe is
it not a dupe um so I think that could
be really cool if integrated long term
into the into the bug Bounty life hack
eventy yeah that's nice yeah yeah this
morning I also I was fuming about some
decision and so it's good that we do
this now and not me shouting at Intel
people or something yeah I mean I think
we've talked about this before but that
is one of the most powerful things about
a live hacking event is that you're on
site with customer and it's really
really hard to have that type of that
same level of communication with that's
like face to face over just you know
posting a comment on your report or
whatever because it may not be you know
you never know which team members going
to read that or if it's triage team or
whatever like instead of you can just
walk up and have a human discussion with
somebody and you can actually just get
to the bottom of it and it's happened
with myself you both I mean both of us
together even on bugs multiple multiple
times at events where we've gone and
we've talked to the customer and we've
been like you know I think there's a
misunderstanding in this bug like here
let me show you and like you know let's
let me see what you CU here's what I see
I don't know if you're seeing the same
thing like let me make sure that we're
on the same page here and maybe if I'm
misunderstanding something you can
explain that to me and you know that
that level of interaction is super super
helpful to just like get to the Botto
bottom of a bug without getting you know
mad and stuff I you know we I won't I
won't disclose anything but one of our
buddies uh he uh he got a little he got
a little trouble he was a little you
know he was a little too raw with with
the customer at one point so you know I
think it's important that you know it's
good to be honest but not not not 100%
all the time so that's that's a nice
thing about being able to just talk with
the customers they can sort of read your
facial expression and all that yeah well
you know the hackers they they've had
you know when you're online there's
always that whole online thing right
like you can you can like you know you
can keyboard War it you know if you want
to but I think people have had more
experience in their lifetime of like oh
well maybe I shouldn't you know be as I
rate if I'm meeting with someone in
person and seeing hey they're just a a
person on the other side of the computer
as well trying to do their best you know
and and I think integrity and and the
the client I guess we'll say for this
event has has done a good job int it's
public okay yeah Intel they they do a
great job with that and particularly
shout out to uh you know Chris flying
toasters um you know he he always throws
great events so uh I I appreciate that
yeah yeah absolutely I um I I was
thinking uh just the other day how uh
having worked in like a professional job
now has changed my communication style
so much like when I was younger before I
had you know worked a corporate job I
would be very raw I would just you know
if it came into my mind I'd just
freaking say it you know and uh now like
you know once you work at a company you
kind of Master the art of uh writing
passive aggressive
emails and you know you you you get good
at like writing something and like I'm
not happy about this thank you very much
have a nice day you know and uh I think
that's really it's that kind of
communication skill is so useful you
know I see it a lot with people who've
you know worked like you've worked at
appsec and at big companies and stuff
and so I think that experience is just
really really valuable yeah I think so
too yeah because especially if you work
like if you're handling incoming book
Bounty reports you have to like sell
someone else's reports within your
organization like this is really
critical you should pick it up you
should drop all the features you're
building and pick this up so that I I
guess that's a useful skill also when
being a buck Bounty Hunter yourself yeah
it's it's so interesting to me when I
hear people in appac talk about like
slas with their own company like you
know they're they're saying like Okay I
can you know I have this agreement that
I've you know negotiated with the you
know programming division like they have
to address our issues within a month and
I'm like this is the same company like
like why is this so complicated but it
you know is in the end and and I've
never even thought about that actually
you know that that the people on on your
side of when you're on the receiving
side of a report you then have to
represent that report to your team to
your developers um so yeah thanks for
all the hard work guys
iome us us uh you know bug Hunters I do
appreciate it whether we say it or not
um you know Renee any other any other
thoughts on the live hacking event I've
got I think maybe one or two I can I can
throw out there but
uh not really you go ahead it's it's
been it's been a good time you know I I
think the for me it's really nice to
meet the Integrity team because it is my
first um live obviously I've spent with
Integrity I've spent time with in before
which is great he's always a pleasure to
see um but particularly like uh
Integrity Travis and and some of the
other guys it's just been really
Pleasant to be around um and it it's
been a really nice experience and I also
really like the structure that they've
done here so with and I guess there's
trade-offs to both but with the hacker
One Life hacking event how it goes is
that you know you fly in you uh you know
do your you know opening cocktail hour
or whatever that either that same day or
the next day if you're International and
then you you do a hacking day and then
you do a community day and and that
Community day is just kind of running
around with friends and and hanging out
and stuff like that and the hacking day
is like pretty much all focused on the
event and that sort of thing um and it
it that's nice in that sense because you
you're done with the hacking at the
community day point and you don't feel
tempted to hack um so I've always been
really a fan of that structure but this
event is also really nice too where they
have multiple hacking days and then
Community stuff in the in the evenings
um because that one it gives you more
time to collab with your with your
friends right um you get to work on the
event a little bit more but also it
forces you to put the bugs down a little
bit and and walk away um I have a really
hard time with that personally so I've
enjoyed the variety in the structure and
um and like I said the team has been
very
accommodating so overall it's been it's
been a pretty cool event the bounties
are still are still rolling in so we'll
see how the the final the final P Justus
is checking his phone right now to see
if he got a
bounty no
Bounty um no but that's that's uh no
fault but my own perhaps and uh so we'll
see how the final payouts roll through
but um overall yeah pretty pretty solid
event so happy happy to have been here
um yeah so I guess we'll we'll close off
there uh Renee thanks for coming on the
pod man and do you said you know I'll
I'll pull up the uh the um socials right
now on uh on on Twitter of course we
have it as Renny Pac and uh that's the
same thing for integrity and then on
LinkedIn I'm going to let you say the
name because I'm going to mispronounce
it no ignore me on LinkedIn okay ignore
him on LinkedIn only go follow on
Twitter and on yeah and visit hacker
hideout. XYZ yes hacker hideout. XYZ
that's another great thing to check out
um where is that specifically uh like
are you guys doing that all within um
within the Netherlands or do you have a
specific City or we don't have a
concrete plan on that yet but we're
trying to we really trying to take it
step by step to well like guarantee the
quality of the community and what's the
Target demographic though Netherlands
residence or not specifically not
specifically gotcha so this could be
bigger than just the Netherlands if you
have a group of actors so the dream is
still to have an office somewhere or
perhaps all around the world but that's
like that's dream dream very cool man
well I I'm looking forward to see you
get it cool thanks guys all right thanks
man
[Music]
thanks